Guide to the Tamara Saviano Collection of Guy and Susanna Clark
The Wittliff Collections
Tamara Saviano Collection of Guy and Susanna Clark
1965-2015
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Saviano, Tamara
SWWC.132
8 Linear Feet
12 boxes
The Tamara Saviano Collection of Guy and Susanna Clark spans the life and careers of both Guy and Susanna Clark with the main focus being on Guy. The collection comprises of Saviano's research for her biography, Without Getting Killed or Caught; interviews, family histories, magazine articles, and donated materials from Guy and Susanna Clark. The organization of the collection is both organic and artificial as the research is left in the order given by Tamara Saviano whereas the personal materials are separated into Guy and Susanna Clark, respectively.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Tamara Saviano, 2016.
Biographical Note
Tamara Saviano was born and raised in Wisconsin but now lives in Nashville, Tennessee, where she has worked as a publicist, music journalist, record and television producer, and artist manager. She has served as president and board member of the Americana Music Association. She also was founder and president of American Roots Publishing, through which she produced the Grammy-award winning CD, Beautiful Dreamer: The Songs of Stephen Foster, as well as the critically-acclaimed album, The Pilgrim: A Celebration of Kris Kristofferson. Saviano is currently a writer, producer and director at Slow Uvalde Films, the production company for Without Getting Killed or Caught: The Life and Music of Guy Clark. Saviano began donating her music archive to the Wittliff Collections in 2007 through the efforts of Dr. Gary Hartman and the Center for Texas Music History at Texas State University.
Guy Clark was a Grammy Award-winning singer, songwriter, and guitarist. He was born November 6, 1941, in Monahans, Texas. Over the course of his career, Guy Clark released more than twenty albums. Many notable artists such as Johnny Cash, Emmylou Harris, Jerry Jeff Walker, Jimmy Buffet, and Rodney Crowell recorded his songs. His last album, My Favorite Picture of You, won the 2014 Grammy Award for Best Folk Album. Guy Clark passed away on May 17, 2016.
Susanna Clark was a songwriter and painter. She was born March 11, 1939 in Atlanta, Texas. In 1969, she met Guy Clark, and the two wed in 1972. Clark wrote "I'll be Your San Antone Rose," among many others. Artists such as Rosanne Cash, Jerry Jeff Walker, David Allen Coe, and Emmylou Harris recorded her songs. Some of her paintings have been used as cover art for albums by Willie Nelson, Emmylou Harris, and her husband, Guy Clark. Susanna Clark passed away on June 27, 2012.
Scope and Contents
The Tamara Saviano Collection of Guy and Susanna Clark spans the life and careers of both Guy and Susanna Clark with the main focus being on Guy. The collection comprises of Saviano's research for her biography, Without Getting Killed or Caught; interviews, family histories, magazine articles, and donated materials from Guy and Susanna Clark. The organization of the collection is both organic and artificial as the research is left in the order given by Tamara Saviano whereas the personal materials are separated into Guy and Susanna Clark, respectively. The collection is organized into these four series: Tamara Saviano's Research, Guy Clark, Susanna Clark, and Audio/Visual Materials.
Index Terms
Subjects
Popular music -- Writing and publishing; Americana (Music); Musicians -- Biography; Musicians -- Interviews
Subjects (Persons)
Saviano, Tamara; Clark, Guy (1941-2016); Clark, Susanna
- Tamara Saviano's Research, 1991-2015
  Series Description
  This series documents Saviano's extensive research for her biography of Guy Clark, Without Getting Killed or Caught. It contains five subseries: Interviews/Interview Questions, Research Files, Photographs, Magazines, and Correspondence
  - Interviews / Interview questions, 1991-2015
    - Keith Sykes, John Lomax III, Fran Lohr, Rodney Crowell, and Bill DeYoung, 1966-2015 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Susanna Clark and Louise O'Connor, May 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Frances Clark, Louise O'Connor, and Guy Clark, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Buddy Mondlock, Gretchen Peters, Wendy Pearl, Louise O'Connor, Alyse Moore, Mickey Raphael, Dave Rawlings, Darrell Scott, Tim O'Brien,Carl Snyder, and Joe Specht, including Louise O'Connor's handwritten notes, 1991-2015 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Townes Van Zandt, Guy Clark, Steve Earle, and Keith Case, 1991-2015 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Guy Clark, Lee Roy Parnell, Donna McKenzie, and Susanna Clark, April 1, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Guy Clark and "Guy Clark: Old School Poet of the World", 2002-2015 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ray Wylie Hubbard, Mary Lucille Jackson, Rick Lambert, Kyle Lehning, Shanna Strassberg, Brennen Leigh, Noel McKay, Richard Leigh, Michael Brovsky, Craig Leon, William Hedgepeth, Kevin Levitan, Terry Allen, Bill Bentley, Rob Bleetstein, and Terry Lickona, 2004-2015 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Caroline Clark, Jan Clark, Travis Clark, Joe Specht, Guy Clark, Kathleen Hudson, Jack Ingram, Ashley Monroe, John Grady, Thomas Gribbin, Gary Overton, Lyle Lovett, and James (no last name), 2004-2015 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Dub Cornett, Lola Bonner, Mary Lucille, and Carl Snyder, 2006-2015 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Guy Clark and Interview Questions, January 3 - December 3, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Guy Clark, December 29, 2010-May 9, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Guy Clark, Steve Earle, Jim McGuire, and Shawn Camp, February 1, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Verlon Thompson and Susanna Clark, February 4-December 16, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Guy Clark, Susanna Clark, and Bill DeYoung, 2011-2014 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Steve Young, Richard Dobson, and various other musicians, 2011-2015 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Guy Clark, Barry Poss, and Jerry Jeff Walker, 2012-2015 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Interview questions for Clark Forbes and Guy Clark, Interviews with Robert Earl Keen, Harold Eggers, and Sherrie Tally, 2013-2015 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Guy Clark Audio Day 1", July 26, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Research Files
    - "Bonner/Chandler-New Cut Road Research"; Research on Bonner Family and Mulberry Hill Schoolhouse, Pre-Twentieth Century, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Guy Clark-Monahans"; Guy Clark's Family and Monahans Research, 1930-1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Guy Clark-Monahans"; Guy Clark's Family and Monahans Research, 1937-2011 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Guy Clark-Rockport"; College transcript, news clippings, and Rockport Visitors Guide, 1962-2012 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Guy Clark-Houston/California"; Lightnin' Hopkins's album covers for "Free Form Patterns", 1965-2011 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "1970s-Press 1975 Old No.1-RCA, 1976 Texas Cookin'-RCA, and 1978 Guy Clark-Warner Bros.", Guy Clark's Biographies and Music Reviews, 1975- 1977, undated; Old No. 1 Reviews and song listing, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Biographies, Articles, and Reviews for Research for the Book on Guy Clark, 1975-2015 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Articles, Reviews, Correspondence, and News Clippings for Research on Book on Guy Clark, 1976-2015 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "1980-1984 Press, 1981 The South Coast of Texas-Warner Bros., 1983 Better Days-Warner Bros."; Music reviews and media information, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "1985-1989 Press, 1989-Old Friends-Sugar Hill"; Music reviews from Rolling Stone and publicity for "Old Friends", 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "1990-1994 Press, Boats to Build 1992 Asylum"; News clippings, articles and reviews for albums and performances, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Louise O'Connor's Notes"; Guy Clark and Townes Van Zandt interviews, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "1995-1999 Press, Dublin Blues 1995, Keeper 1997, Cold Dog Soup 1999"; various news clippings including "Old Friends" album, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "2000-2004 Press, 2002-The Dark"; Reviews and publicity, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Mother Texas"; Drafts include a list of participants and possible participants, 2000-2011 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Joe Specht, emails, 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "2005-2009 Press and reviews; Workbench Songs-2006, 2007-Live from Austin, TX, 2009-"Somedays the Song Writes You"-Dualtone"; Reviews and News Clippings, 2006-2010 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Articles and reviews about Guy Clark's music and performances, 2000-2007 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Guy Clark-Nashville, Songwriting Info & Publishing"; Research about Guy Clark's songs, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "2010-2014 Press"; Articles on "My Favorite Picture of You" and Guy Clark's biography (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Articles about Susanna Clark's passing, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Journal of Tamara Saviano's Research Notes, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Short biography of Guy Clark by Tamara Saviano for the Guy Clark Archives, circa 2016 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, 2010-2011, undated
    - Photography stills of Guy Clark and various singers such as Emmylou Harris, Julie Miller, Robert Earl King, Justin Townes Earl, Robert Plant from HSB Festival, San Francisco taken by Michael Riley, 2011-2012 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Two CDs with Photos of Guy Clark at the HSB Festival, San Francisco, 2010-2011 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "Guy Clark Book Scan", 13 photos, McGuire, DVD, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Magazines, 1977, 2002-2015
    - Tennessee's Original Music Magazine August, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Farwest Almanac, Texas Music and No Depression magazines featuring Guy Clark, 2002-2009 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Texas Music and American Songwriter, 2008-2013 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Austin Chronicle "Guy Clark In The Raw" (3 copies), July 19, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Nashville Scene "Life on the Wall" (4 copies, July 25-31, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - No Depression and The Roots Music Authority Magazine, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Emails with Joanne Gardner, Don Cusic, and Ben Vaughn including English 1301 Class Project on Clark's music, 2011-2012 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Guy Clark, 1979-1992
  This series is broken down into three subseries: Correspondence, Personal Materials, and Photographs.
  - Correspondence: Letters, cards, postcards, invitations, and fax, including a wedding reception invitation from Rosanne Cash and Rodney Crowell, 1979-1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Guy Clark's Sheet Music for "The Last Gunfighter Ballad" (1976), "Oklahoma Borderline" (1985), and "Baby I'm Yours" (1988) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Willie Nelson Backstage Passes and Willie Nelson Official Fan Club Newsletter, Vol. 2 No.11, January 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Certificate of Justice of the Peace for Ellis L. Clark (1979), Guy Clark: Cambridge and Galway (1988), Demo tape track listing for "Headout" by Guy Clark (undated), Luckenbach Monthly Moon (1978), Educational Coloring Book of Texas: 1836-1986, Music Row Vol. 3 No. 7 October 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Receipts for shows for Guy Clark with Townes Van Zandt, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Program and Invitations to Guy Clark's 70th Birthday Tribute, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Guitar Shaped USB with pictures from Guy Clark's 70th Birthday Tribute, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Promotional Materials including Cactus Cafe and Kerrville Folk Festival, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Three Guy Clark Press Kits Free Flow, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Four Photosets of Guy Clark: Two Photos for Asylum Records by Señor McGuire, One Photo for Sugar Hill by Keith Case and Associates, One Photo for Dual Tone by Keith Case and Associates, 1994-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Susanna Clark, 1961-1997
  This series is composed of five subseries: Correspondence, Personal Materials, Photographs, Artwork, and Awards.
  - Letters, cards, and gift telegrams including a poem by Gaylon Stacy, 1963-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Letter, e-mails, cards, and gift telegrams including postcards from Emmylou Harris, 1992-2002 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Notepad, Wedding Invitation (Susanna's first marriage), Talley Family roster, John D. Talley's birth certificate (copy), article by Teddy Allen, The "True Talley" Test, and Susanna's Parent's marriage license, 1961, 1995, 1996, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Oklahoma Science and Arts Foundation Junior Science summer classes, Toward the Golden Age "John Skelton", Sociology Essay and Obituary for Eleanor Kirkpatrick, 1963, 1997, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "An Ode to 1939 in View of Becoming 29" to Susanna from Brunel, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sheet music for "I'll Be Your San Antone Rose", Sunbury Music, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Calendars, 1988 and 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Handwritten notes and lyrics, 1989-1996, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Royalty statement for "You're a Hard Dog to Keep (under the Porch), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Magazine and newspaper articles, Domestic Affairs newsletter, and press release about Joyce Maynard, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Susanna Clark's Obituary and photograph of Susanna Clark, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Susanna and photograph of the sky titled, "Light for Susanna" by Don Michael Sampson, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 6 photographs of Susanna Clark including a picture with Rodney Crowell, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Awards, 1976-1990
    - The American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers Award of Merit to Susanna Clark, Writer of the Outstanding Country Song "I'll Be Your San Antone Rose,", October 13, 1976 (Box 8)
    - The American Society of Composers Authors and Publishers Award of Merit to Susanna Clark for her song "Easy From Now On", October 10, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Panama Red's Number One Customer for Susanna Clark, June 29, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 1990 ASCAP Country Award, Honors Susanna Clark, writer of "Come from the Heart", October 10, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Artwork by Susanna Clark, undated
    - Unidentified person. Acrylic painting on canvas (Box 9)
    - Pink flowers. Acrylic painting on canvas (Box 9)
    - Pink and purple flowers. Acrylic painting on canvas (Box 9)
    - Orange lily drawing (Box 9)
    - "Mother." Painting (Box 9)
    - Watercolor painting (Box 9)
- Audio/Visual Material
  This series consists of five subseries: 45rpm Records, Cassette Tapes, Compact Discs, VHS Tapes, and U-Matic Master Tapes.
  - 45 rpm Records, 1977-1980
    - "Heartbroke" written and performed by Guy Clark, 45 rpm (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "I'll Be Your San Antone Rose" written by Susanna Clark and performed by Emmylou Harris, 45rpm record (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "The Old Mother's Locket Trick",written by Guy Clark and performed by Harold Lee, 45 rpm (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Audio Cassette Tapes, 2008-2012
    - "Keith Case", May 31, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Guy Clark", June 1, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Guy Clark", collaboration with Verlon Thompson and Shawn Camp, December 9, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Rodney Crowell"/ "Emmylou Harris", May 21-23, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Vince Gill on Guy Clark" A Side/ "Rodney Crowell on Guy Clark" B Side, May 21-23, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Compact Discs, 2000-2002
    - "Guy Clark & Verlon Thompson, Paris, Hotel du Nord, 7/23-24/02", CD, July 23-24, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Mary Lucille" (2 CDs), April 14, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Texas Book #7 & #8 Guy Clark, cont'd Tape 1B & 2A", Tamara Saviano, CD copy, April 1, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Texas Book #7 Guy Clark Tape (A & B), Tamara Saviano, CD copy, April 1, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Texas Book #8 Guy Clark, cont'd Tape 2b", Tamara Saviano, CD copy, April 1, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - VHS Cassette Tapes, 1989-1995, undated
    - "A Celebration of Townes Van Zandt", VHS, December 7, 1997 (Box 10)
    - "American Music Shop", Show #909307, Spryland Productions of VHS (Box 10)
    - "Austin City Limits Guy Clark", Season 15, dub of studio master, VHS, December 5, 1989 (Box 10)
    - "Austin City Limits #103 Townes Van Zandt/ Austin City Limits #802 West Texas Songwriters Special", VHS (Box 10)
    - "Baton Rouge", Guy Clark, Asylum Records, Elektra Entertainment, VHS (Box 10)
    - "Baton Rouge" TRT 2:44", VHS (Box 10)
    - "Boats to Build-Guy Clark", Asylum Records, VHS (2 copies) (Box 10)
    - "Boats to Build" TRT 3:47", VHS (Box 10)
    - "Guy Clark ASCAP Lifetime Achievement Award", VHS Master (2 copies) (Box 11)
    - "Guy Clark BIO", Asylum Records, VHS (Box 11)
    - "Guy Clark BIO", Director Miller/Murano/Sharp, VHS (Box 11)
    - "Guy Clark BIO: Nonesuch/ American Explorer/ Asylum Records", VHS (Box 11)
    - "Guy Clark BIO" TRT 9:06", VHS (Box 11)
    - "Home Grown Tomatoes", VHS (Box 11)
    - "Live from the Bluebird Café Show #218 Hal Ketchum, Guy Clark, Verlon Thompson", Studio Productions, VHS (Box 11)
    - "Music City Tonight", TNN Network, VHS, May 31, 1995 (Box 11)
    - "Nashville Cats", Wild Child, with correspondence to Guy Clark,VHS (Box 11)
    - "Nashville Now!", Show No. 42124, VHS (Box 11)
    - "Nashville Skyline", Emmylou Harris w/special guests Angel Band, VHS, 1993 (Box 11)
  - U-Matic Master Tapes, 1992, undated
    - "Baton Rouge", serial no. 8436, Master U-Matic (Box 12)
    - "Guy Clark Biography", serial no. 8446, Master U-Matic, Asylum Records, December 23, 1992 (Box 12)
    - "Guy Clark-"Boats to Build", serial no. 8439, Master U-Matic, Asylum Records (Box 12)